# **David Thomas**

Thiruvananthapuram Taluk, Kerala, India



dit.in7@gmail.com



+91 9074238808



linkedin.com/in/djtin

### **Summary**

Software Engineer with professional experience in building complete solutions with JavaScript/TypeScript and deploying

them with popular options like AWS, Heroku or GCP.

Strong foundations in software architectural design and software engineering principles.

Able to adapt to any environment and deliver battle-tested software. Framework agnostic.

### **Experience**



### 🔇 Software Engineer

**Experion Technologies** 

Apr 2020 - Present (10 months +)

- Working with clients to enhance and maintain the backend and web client of a SaaS platform that assists dementia patients in performing daily activities (AWS/Postgresql/MERN).
- Worked on a data extraction application in the construction domain (AWS/PostgresqlL/DynamoDB/ Python/Node.js/React.js).
- Worked on refactoring an existing healthcare application (AWS/MEAN).
- Led a full-stack development training program for new recruits (Heroku/MERN).

# Android App Developer

Self-employed

Jan 2020 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

I develop Android apps in my personal time.

# 🔇 Associate Software Engineer

**Experion Technologies** 

Nov 2018 - Apr 2020 (1 year 6 months)

- Worked on developing an application for enabling dementia patients to perform daily tasks. The application was awarded the first-prize grant by the NIA (AWS/Postgresql/MERN).
- Worked on automating the testing suite for a TTS application (Audio Routing).
- Worked on developing designs for a visual map application (SSR with Node.is/HTML5/Pdf.is).

# 🔇 Software Engineering Trainee

**Experion Technologies** 

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018 (5 months)

- Worked on a retail management system (Postgresql/.NET Core/C#/Angular).
- Worked on a booking application (AWS/MEAN).
- Worked on a sentiment analysis application (MEAN).

#### **Education**

Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science 2014 - 2018

(A) freeCodeCamp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering 2017 - 2018

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- in Node.js: Microservices LinkedIn
- DevOps Foundations: Lean and Agile LinkedIn
- in Advanced Python LinkedIn
- in AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (SAA-C01): 1 Cloud Services
  Overview (2019) LinkedIn
- Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End LinkedIn
- Algorithmic Trading and Stocks Essential Training LinkedIn
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (SAA-C01): 4 Compute Services LinkedIn
- Node.js: Real-Time Web with Socket.IO LinkedIn
- in Learning Kubernetes LinkedIn
- in Algorithmic Trading and Finance Models with Python, R, and Stata Essential Training LinkedIn
- TypeScript: Object-Oriented Programming LinkedIn
- node.js: Design Patterns LinkedIn

- in Node.js: Testing and Code Quality LinkedIn
- Flutter: Part 01 Introduction LinkedIn
- in Node.js: Security LinkedIn
- m Microservices: Design Patterns LinkedIn
- Programming Foundations: APIs and Web Services LinkedIn
- Rest API (Intermediate) Certificate HackerRank f28715b7341f
- CutShort Certified Javascript Advanced CutShort 25873
- Problem Solving HackerRank
- Being The Baus LinkedIn
  David isn't a dull boy and loves to joke around

#### **Skills**

Node.js • JavaScript • PostgreSQL • Data Structures • Database Design • Web Development • Cloud Computing • Front-end Development • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • React Native

#### **Honors & Awards**

Certificate of Merit - Director's Honours List - Amal Jyothi College of Engineering
May 2015

Certificate of highest academic merit.

Certificate of Merit - Director's Honours List - Amal Jyothi College of Engineering
Nov 2015

Certificate of highest academic merit.

Initial Learning Programme - Faith Infotech Academy

Nov 2018

An introductory course to software engineering principles and methodologies along with web development with .NET Core and JavaScript.